看
Look!
- 那是什么 - 是个Dalek 快躲起来!
- What is it? - A Dalek. Take cover!
消灭
ExterminateI
消灭 消灭
ExterminateI ExterminateI
- 他们从哪儿冒出来的 - 时间走廊
- Where did they come from? - The Time Corridor.
- 从你的船上 - 肯定是
- Your ship? - Must be.
- 他们想怎么样 - 我们这就把原因找出来吧
- What do they want? - Let's not find out.
瞄准那圆顶上的目镜
Aim for the eyepiece on the dome.
视力受损 我看不到了
My vision is impaired I cannot see
My vision is impaired  I cannot see
- 快点儿 - 我看不到了
- Quickly! - I cannot see
我看不到了 警告  我的视力受损了
I cannot see  Warning  Warning  My vision is impaired
- 把门打开 - 我看不到  我看不到
- Open the door! - I cannot see  I cannot see
警告 紧急情况
Warning  Emergency
她没事 我们应该带她到楼下
She's all right. We should get her downstairs.
你去做那个 我需要人手帮我处理外面的Dalek碎片
While you're doing that, I'd like a hand with the debris outside.
派去仓库的Dalek 被毁坏了
The Dalek sent to the warehouse has been destroyed.
怎么可能
How is that possible?
博士有地球上的士兵帮助
The Doctor was aided by the Earth soldiers.
封锁时光走廊的 仓库出入口
Seal the warehouse terminal of the Time Corridor.
我们还是用 适当的程序来对付博士
We will deal with the Doctor in due course.
- 我们要去哪里 - 戴好面罩
- Where are we going? - Keep your mask down.
- 周围可能还有毒气 - 那又怎样 我宁愿快点死掉
- There could still be gas around. - So what? I'd rather die quickly.
我们在这儿待了多久了
How long are we going to wander around?
据我所知 只有我们四个还活着
As far as we know, there are only four of us still alive.
- 我们不能孤身对抗Dalek - 你想战斗到底
- We can't fight the Daleks alone. - You wanted to fight to the end.
看看他们所到之处 一堆死人
Look where it got me. A dead crew.
既然这样 那就不要让他们白白牺牲
Then don't let it be for nothing.
我们能做些什么
What can we do?
你忘了这个地方有一套自毁系统吗
Have you forgotten this station has a self-destruct system?
他很安静
He's very still.
他死了吗
Is he dead?
我想没有
I think not.
马上就准备好了
Soon be ready.
我们可以用更强大的东西来做这个
We could do with something stronger.
- 楼上你朋友怎么样了 - 他死了
- How's your friend upstairs? - He's dead.
- 她怎么样了 - 睡着了
- How is she? - She's sleeping naturally.
-喝茶吗 长官 -谢谢
-Tea, sir? -Thank you.
是谁找到这些圆柱的
Who discovered these cylinders?
当施工人员把这个仓库改造成公寓的时候
Builders converting the warehouse into flats.
我想这是尚未爆炸的炸弹
Thought they were unexploded bombs.
- 你有试过打开一个看看吗 - 都没试过抓一下它
- Have you tried to open one? - Haven't even scratched it.
Dalek跟这些有关系吗
Have the Daleks anything to do with this?
如果跟他们没关系那也太巧了
It would be an enormous coincidence if they didn't.
你是谁
Who are you?
- Lytton司令 - 司令
- Commander Lytton. - Commander?
- 我的Dalek不需要部队 - 没有我的话 你还在监狱里
- My Daleks do not need troopsI - You'd be in prison without my men.
你说的好像我的Dalek 再不能战斗了一样
You speak as though my Daleks are no longer capable of war.
在你服刑期间发生了很多事情
A lot has happened during your imprisonment.
跟Movellans的战争结束了
The war with the Movellans is over?
是的 尽管伤亡惨重
Yes, although casualties were very high.
喜闻乐见
It is to be expected.
我说的是Dalek伤亡惨重
I'm talking about Dalek casualties.
Dalek...伤亡惨重
Dalek...casualties?
他们输了, Davros. 他们完全被打败了
They lost, Davros. They were totally defeated.
0-3呼叫总部 0-3呼叫总部 结束
0-3 to HQ? 0-3 to HQ? Over.
- 一直试 别停 - 你必须要得到增援
- Keep trying. - You must get reinforcements.
我不能把他们从空气中变出来 我需要一部电话
I can't conjure them out of the air. I need a telephone.
- 我去吧 你在这里还有用 - 这不仅仅是军事
- I'll go. You're needed here. - It's more than a military matter.
我必须跟国防部通话  我们需要大部队增援
I have to speak to the MOD. We'll need massive troop involvement.
我跟你一起去
I'll come with you.
你是唯一一个知道怎么对付Dalek的人
You're the only one who knows anything about fighting Daleks.
你守在这里
Your duty's here.
他是博士的同伴之一
He is a companion of the Doctor.
他应该被毁灭
He should be destroyed.
把他当作诱饵更好
He would be better used as bait.
博士敏感多情 而又易感情用事
The Doctor is sentimental and emotional.
他会来找这孩子的
He will come after the boy.
这有利于Dalek的计划
This will aid the Dalek plan.
让那个男孩四处游荡
Allow the boy to roam freely.
我们休息一会儿
We'll rest for a moment.
你们都不突发奇想吗 我想拿一切换一杯矿泉水
Don't you get funny ideas? I'd give anything for a glass of spring water.
安静!
Quiet!
卧倒!
Down!
开火!
Fire!
小心点儿.
Careful.
穿上他们的制服!
Uniforms!
穿上他们的制服
Uniforms.
快 喝下这个 对你的头有好处
Here. Take these. It'll help your head.
我不能在这儿太久 必须要回到船上去
I won't be long. I must get back to my ship.
- 长官... - 我必须找到Turlough
- Sir... - I must find Turlough.
- 可以, 但是请等着上校 - 不, Turlough在Dalek的飞船上
- Yes, but wait for the Colonel. - No, Turlough's on the Dalek ship.
- 他不会太久的 - 让他走
- He won't be long. - Let him go.
我不能
I can't.
救我!
Help!
- 我们运气不大好 - 小心点儿!
We're out of luck - be careful!
- 吓死了 那是个Dalek - 是的 一个尸体而已
- I was terrified it was a Dalek. - It was. The remains of one.
他还活着
He's still alive.
我们必须在他再次试图杀戮之前找到他
We have to find it before it tries to kill again.
你还好吗
You all right?
我的生命维护系统 有些问题
There are malfunctions in my life-support system.
- 我需要个工程师 - 我们必须登上Dalek的飞船
- I require an engineer. - We must board the Dalek ship.
我离不开我的冷冻室
I must remain close to my cryogenic chamber.
我可能需要重新被冷冻
I may need to be re-frozen.
这儿有时间因素 空间站发送了一个遇险信号
There is a time factor. The space station transmitted a distress call.
军队要花好几天时间 到达这里
It will take days for troops to arrive.
如果信号被巡逻舰拦截就不会到达
Not if the signal's been intercepted by a patrol ship.
那你把它射中吧 我动不了
Then you will shoot it down  I cannot be moved
找个工程师来维修Davros
Order an engineer to attend Davros.
我们应该马上离开这儿
We should leave here at once.
没Davros,我们没有未来
Without Davros, we have no future.
我们一定要让他相信 我们服务于他
He must be made to believe that we serve him.
这是在浪费时间  变异体利用了时间走廊
This is a waste of time. The mutant could have used the Time Corridor.
没错 那你为什么在那里踌躇的寻找
True. So why be so tentative in your search?
- 我们还不能确切的知道 - 那就是我们寻找的原因
- We don't know for certain. - That's why we're searching
- 它看起来像什么 - 你不会弄错它的
- What does it look like? - You won't mistake it.
当你看到它 它会试图杀了你
The moment you find it, it'll try and kill you.
先生你 你们救了我
Gentlemen, you've saved my life.
我是Archer上校, 服务于炸弹处理小队
I'm Colonel Archer, Bomb Disposal Squad.
我要进行紧急呼叫 可以用你的无线电吗
I have to make an urgent call. May I use your radio?
请给我
Please.
谢谢
Thank you.
它坏了
It's dead.
跟我说说Dalek战败的事
Tell me about the Dalek defeat.
你知道的几乎是全部了
You already know most of it.
Dalek和Movellan陷入了僵局
The Daleks and the Movellans were locked in an impasse.
每次一方制定一个策略,
Each time one attempted a stratagem,
都会被对方的战争电脑识破和进行反击
it was anticipated and countered by their opponent's battle computer.
两部完全的逻辑战争机器 彼此不能以智取胜
Two totally logical war machines unable to out-think each other?
- 太妙了 要是我在那儿就好了 - Movellan掌握了制胜先机
- FascinatingI If only I'd been there. - The Movellans found the answer.
对不起, 先生
Sorry, sir.
快点, 告诉我
Quickly, tell me.
他们发明了一种专门对付Dalek的病毒
They developed a virus which exclusively attacks the Daleks.
整个舰队都被摧毁了 为了防止被感染 这些幸存的都逃走了
The fleet was destroyed. Those who survived fled to escape infection
现在在找治愈方法
and work on a cure.
- 找到了吗 - 还没有
- Have they succeeded? - Not yet.
所以...他们回到了 他们的创造者这里
So...they have returned to their creator.
就像犯了错的孩子, 他们再一次回家了.
Like an errant child, they have come home once more.
不过这次, 他们不能再虐待我了
But this time, they will not abuse me.
这次, 我将行使作为他们 君主的权利,
This time, I shall take my rightful place as their supreme being,
在我的控制下Dalek 会再一次天下无敌
and under my control, the Daleks shall once more become triumphantI
- 你能研究出解药吗 - 毫无疑问
- Can you find an antidote? - Of course.
- 已经找遍了方法 - 我是Davros.
- Research has been done. - I am Davros.
我创造了Dalek
The Daleks are my creation.
必要的话 我会对他们 进行基因重组 你弄好了吗
If necessary, I shall genetically re-engineer them. Have you finished?
- 快了, 长官 - 我需要实验室
- Almost, sir. - I will need a laboratory.
- 已经给你准备了一个 - 我就在这个空间站上工作
- There's one prepared for you. - I shall work here on the station.
我已经解释过了 没时间了
I've explained. There isn't time.
我不能冒险 如果 病毒四散到Dalek的飞船上...
I cannot risk an accident. If the virus escaped on the Dalek ship...
- 已经采取了预防措施 - 要么让我在这儿做
- Every precaution has been taken. - I work here
要么我就不做
Or not at all.
我看看怎么安排吧
I'll see what can be arranged.
快点儿 还有很多事要做.
Hurry. There is much work to be done.
我弄好了
I've finished.
关闭仪表板
Close the panel.
我命令你服从于Davros
I order you to obey Davros.
如果突击队从地球上来了会怎么样
What happens when the task force arrives from Earth?
我们应该离开 我有个计划
We shall be gone. I have a plan that will force Davros
可以逼Davros离开
to leave of his own free will.
到那时候, 你必须供给他 所要求的一切
Until then, you must supply him with everything he demands.
让他进入空间站 的实验室
Allow him access to the space station's laboratory.
一切都听你的
As you command.
- 怎么了 - 小意外
- What happened? - A small accident.
- 你还好吗 - 我抓到了自己的手 没事
- Are you all right? - I caught my hand. It's nothing.
不是这儿 我们还没找到时间走廊的入口
It isn't here. We haven't found the entrance to the Time Corridor either.
我想暂时还连接不上
Temporarily disconnected, I would think.
博士...
Doctor...
- 那是什么 - 没有 什么都没有
- What is it? - Nothing. Nothing.
继续找
Go on with the search.
对宇宙的征服者来说这太过了
So much for the conqueror of the universe.
我告诉你它已经走了
I told you it had gone.
- 它死了吗  - 你要不要自己去看一下
- Is it dead? - Would you care to take a look?
他怎么样
How is he?
只是受惊了 身体应该没事
It's more shock than physical.
过来 孩子 我们带你去楼下
Come on, lad. Let's get you downstairs.
- 怎么了 - Dalek还没死透透
- What happened? - The Dalek wasn't quite dead.
- 拿着 - 帮我一把
- Here. - Give us a hand.
好的
Of course.
我必须要找到Dalek的飞船
I have to find the Dalek ship.
我不去那里了 他们会杀了我的
I'm not going back there. They'll kill me.
- 我需要你来帮我 - 你不知道我胆子多小
- I need your help. - You don't know what a coward I am.
刚好给你一个展示的机会 过来
You can take this opportunity to show me. Come along.
- 杀了他! - 等等 先审审他
- Kill him! - Wait. Question him first.
怎么了 那枪声是怎么回事
What happened? What was that shooting?
Dalek的一个小问题
A small problem with a Dalek.
- 他在这儿会舒服点儿 - 待这儿别动
- He'd be more comfortable here. - Stay there.
看起来只是破了皮
It looks superficial.
但愿里面没毒 可能是外星人造成的
As long as there's no poison in it. It was caused by an alien.
不知道是什么进入了他的血液
We don't know what may have entered his bloodstream.
上校马上就回来了 我们要把他们俩都送进医院
The Colonel will be back soon. We get them both to hospital.
我在那里冻了九十年
Ninety years I was frozen in that.
九十年的 心烦意乱
Ninety years of mind-numbing boredom.
- 那时候你有意识吗 - 每一秒都有
- You were conscious? - Every second.
地球上的那些生物 没兴趣对人执行死刑
The creatures of Earth have no stomach for judicial murder.
他们更喜欢让你 慢慢腐烂直到死去
They prefer to leave you to slowly rot and die.
这就是他们所谓的人道主义
They call it being humane.
那你也以其人之道还治其人之身
Then you must be equally humane in your revenge.
那是一个我应该毁灭的星球 被我好整以暇的毁灭
It is a planet I shall destroy at my leisure.
但是首先我必须要对付 一个爱管闲事的时间领主
But first, I must deal with a meddling Time Lord.
- 那是众望所归的 - 你抓到了博士
- That's been anticipated. - You have the Doctor?
分分钟的事儿
His capture is imminent.
很好
ExcellentI
一旦我榨干他的脑子 获得所有的知识,
Once I have drained his mind of all knowledge,
他就慢慢等死吧 痛入骨髓的死吧
he shall then die slowly and painfullyI
这是他最后一次介入了
He has interfered for the last time.
- 别这样! - 不要看 如果这让你不舒服的话
- Don't! - Don't look if it offends you.
- 看, 他什么都不知道 - 他不是船上的人
- Look, he doesn't know anything. - He's not one of the crew.
- 他一定是跟Dalek一起的 - 我来自地球
- He must be with the Daleks. - I'm from Earth.
- 那么 你是怎么到这儿的 - 从Dalek的时间走廊
- Then, how did you get here? - The Daleks' Time Corridor.
- 你们相信吗 - 为什么不 我们知道Dalek无所不能
- Do you believe that? - We know the Daleks are capable.
- 那我们让他进来吧 - 不
- So we're letting him go. - No,
但是我们不能在这儿等着Dalek找到我们
but we're not waiting here for the Daleks to find us, either.
- 有人要喝茶吗  - 不用 谢谢
- Anyone want some tea? - No, thanks.
我好希望上校回来 他还要多久
I'd rather have the Colonel back. How much longer will he be?
喂 你去哪儿 孩子
Hey, where are you going, lad?
过来 你这样子就不用执行任务...
Come on. You're excused duties...
- 你还好吗 - 是的 你待这儿别动
- Are you all right? - Yeah. You stay there.
他是怎么了
What's that about?
刺激通向 时光走廊的出口
Activate the exit to the Time Corridor.
我们服从
We obey.
快点儿 孩子
Come on, lad.
不用担心
There's nothing to worry about.
那是Calder警官
It's only Sergeant Calder.
上校去找救护车了 你一会儿就会好的
The Colonel's gone for an ambulance. You'll be all right.
消灭 消灭
ExterminateI ExterminateI
Exterminate  Exterminate
消灭 消灭
Exterminate Exterminate
Exterminate  Exterminate
- 有枪声 - 快点儿 我们应该出去
- That was gunfire. - Quickly! We should get out.
快点儿
Quickly!
没什么好担心的 回去吧
There's nothing to worry about.
我去通知他 实验室准备好了
I'll inform him at once. Your laboratory is ready.
好 我需要 药剂师的帮助
Good. I will require the assistance of a chemist.
- 好的 -  Kiston出来
- Of course. - And Kiston.
他是很有能力的 机械工程师
He has proven to be a competent mechanical engineer.
如你所愿
As you wish.
- 卫兵 - 保卫好他们
- Guards? - An escort.
这儿还有大批的工作人员
There are still some crew at large.
这纯粹是一个预防措施
It's purely a precaution.
我很难被杀的 你早应该知道
I am very difficult to kill. You should already know that.
那不是Archer上校
That's not Colonel Archer.
他把他的枪和腰带给了博士, 但是这个还戴着
He gave the Doctor his gun belt, yet he's wearing one.
- 你们在小声的聊什么 - 救护车什么时候来
- What are you whispering about? - When will the ambulance arrive?
- 一会儿就到 - 增援人员呢
- That is in hand. - The reinforcements?
这是军事秘密
That is a military matter and therefore confidential.
我想我们不应该再等救护车了
I don't think we'll wait for the ambulance.
仓库处于军事管制中
This warehouse is under martial law.
试图离开会被枪决
Attempt to leave and I'll have you shot.
就是它了 我已经锁定了Dalek的飞船
That's it. I've located the Dalek ship.
等我接到Tegan就放你下去
I'll drop you off when I collect Tegan.
- 我跟你一起去 - 你真好人
- I'll come with you. - Good man.
我们看到博士的Tardis 已经在时光走廊里了
The Doctor's Tardis has been caught in the Time Corridor.
- 准备复制车间 - 遵命
- Prepare the duplication room. - I obey.
Turlough
Turlough?
傻孩子...嘘!
Foolish boy...Shh!
快点儿! 我们离开这里吧
Quickly! Let's get out of here.
不, 博士
No, Doctor.
真是疯了
This is madness.
Dalek不会因为你抓到我就感谢你的  它们会杀了你
The Daleks won't thank you for capturing me. They'll kill you.
我没有完全说实话
I didn't quite tell the truth.
我服务于Dalek 我们它们的特工
I serve the Daleks. I'm a Dalek agent.
iCelery军团倾情奉献
神秘博士
第21季 第4集
{\fnMicrosoft YaHei\fs20\bord1\shad2\an8\1c&H000000&\3c&HFFFFFF&\fad(195,60)\move(195,60.8,195,00)}iCelery军团倾情奉献
{\fnMicrosoft YaHei\fs36\bord1\shad2\an8\1c&H000000&\3c&HFFFFFF&\fad(195,190)\move(195,190,195,280)}神秘博士
{\fnMicrosoft YaHei\fs18\bord1\shad2\an8\1c&H000000&\3c&HFFFFFF&\fad(195,230)\move(195,230,195,300)}第21季 第4集
戴立克的复兴
校对：NO MORE
翻译：nancydodo
第二部分
本字幕根据知识共享-署名-相同方式共享-4.0国际（CC-BY-SA4.0)协议发布
http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/deed.zh
翻译：nancydodo 校对：NO MORE
后期：小鱼干 监制：于昊源
iCelery
军团